강하게... 곱게...
Strong and gentle...
우리는 SUPER GUYS
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
메다로트: 혼
Medarot: Spirits
(Medarotto Damashī)
무적의 히로야!!
We are matchless heroes!!
태어난 그 순간이
The very moment of being born
기적을 부르는 사랑과 정의
It is the love and justice calling for a miracle
멀리 떨어져 있어도
Even when separated by distance
믿는 불꽃의 혼
The spirit of flame believes in each other
흘러라 빛나는 땀!
Flow! Sparkling sweat!
불타는 혼
Burning spirit!
둘이서라면 무한의 파워!
When there are two, infinite power shows itself!
꿈이여 펼쳐져라!
Let dreams unfold!
우리는 SUPER GUYS!
WE ARE SUPER GUYS!
고고한 히로야!!
We are lonely yet proud heroes!!
라디오 컨트롤이라는 거 멋져!
Radio controlling; how cool is that!?
그렇지? 최신 플라이트 시뮬레이터보다 조종감이 훨씬 뛰어나!
You know it! It feels much better than the one in flight simulators.
네, 완전 대단해요, 이거!
Yeah, this is so awesome!
복엽기의 플라이트감을 여기까지 재현하는데 꽤나 고생했어. 인터페이스의 테이퍼를 27% 증가시켰고.
It took a while to emulate the flight experience to this extent. I had to apply 27% more tapers for the interface.
그래도 그래선 관리 시스템의 균형이 무너지지 않나요?
But if you do that, the management system's balance would collapse, doesn't it?
어라, 잘 알고 있구나.
Hey, you know that well.
아, 그건...
Oh, thanks...
그래서 강철의 균형을 조정하려고 구동계의 파츠는 내가 금형부터 만들기도 했어.
For that, I made the molds for driving unit to balance the metals used.
저 복엽기는 내가 기계에 관심을 가지게 된 계기야.
That biplane served as a momentum to my interest in making machines.
소중한 거네요.
It's something so deary to you.
메타비도 그만큼이나 소중하게 생각해.
Metabee also is as precious as that.
내가 마음을 담아 조정한 동체니까.
I've adjusted his body with all my heart.
들었냐, 잇키! 내 동체는 나에 씨의 마음이 담겨 있어! 어떠냐! 내가 이겼지!
Did you hear that, Ikki!? Ms. Nae poured all his heart to my body! How's that!? I win!
우쭐대지 말랬지?
Again, don't get puffed up!
뭔 짓이야!
What was that for!?
어라? 어떻게 된 거야?
Huh? What's going on?
똑바로 컨트롤러 잡고 있지 않으니까 그러는 거 아니냐?
Isn't that because you're holding the controller wrong?
그런 거 아냐! 봐봐, 기체가 반응하지 않잖아.
That's not it! Look, the plane isn't responding.
이상하네. 충분히 전파가 닿을 높이인데.
That's not right. It's not flying too high to become unable to respond.
저거 뭐야?
What's that?
하늘에서 전투!
Battle in Sky!
(en: Title Flight)
부서졌네...
It's wrecked...
저거 뭐야?
What's that?
데스 메다로트?
A Death Medarot?
코쿠류!
Kokuryu!
어라라? 이런 구식 라디오 컨트롤하고 혼신된 거야?
Huh? Did it suffer interference with an old radio controlled machine?
컨트롤러가 최신인 VGR 타입입니다.
Its controller is rather new VGR type.
그건 유도 장치로 데스 메다로트하고 같은 DSQ형 칩을 쓰기 때문입니다.
And that means both Death Medarot and that use the same DSQ-type chip as guiding device.
-그렇구나.
-야, 코쿠류!
-I see.
-Hey, Kokuryu!
나에 씨 복엽기를 부순 주제에 그 태도는 뭐냐!? 사과해!
After you destroyed Ms. Nae's plane, what kind of attitude is that!? Apologize!
잠깐. 이건 사고잖아. 왜 내가 사과해야 해?
Hey, wait. This is just an accident. Why do I have to?
-뭐시라?
-난 신형 데스 메다로트 비행 테스트를 하고 있었을 뿐이야.
-What did you say?
-I was just testing the flight of new Death Medarot.
그러더니 우연히 유도 전파가 혼신됐어. 그래도 난 그 정도로 너희한테 뭐라고 하진 않잖아?
During that, there was interference with the guiding signals, but I don't blame you guys, do I?
야!
Why, you..
HWK형 플라이팔콘
HWK Type Flyfalcon
야, 임마! 니가 부딛혀서 부서졌잖아! 너도 사과해라, 이 새꺄!
Hey, you! It got destoryed because you crashed into it! You should apologize too!
야, 달아나냐!? 멈춰!
What, running away!? Stop right there!
메타비!
Metabee!
플라이팔콘! 명령은 내리지 않았어! 돌아와!
Flyfalcon! I didn't command you anything! Come back!
어디 못 갈 테다!
You aren't going anywhere!
젠장! 잘도 나에 씨 기계를!
Damn! How dare you do that to Ms. Nae's plane!?
틀렸어. 전파가 닿는데도 반응하지 않네.
It's no good. It's not responding, despite that it's receiving signals.
헤드 파츠네요. 명령 전달 게이트가 부서졌다거나...
Must be a problem with the head part. Maybe its command transmitting gates are broken...
부서졌다니!?
It broke!?
야!
Hey!
우라가스미, 알지?
Uragasumi, you know what to do.
알겠습니다. 법리에 대해선 연구소에 제가 보고하겠습니다.
No need to tell more. I'll let the lab deal with the legal matters.
야, 뭐야, 그 빨간 메달은?
Hey, what's with that red medal?
자폭 시퀀스의 스타트 키야.
It's a start key for self-destruction sequence.
자폭!?
Self-destruct!?
저건 프로토타입이니까. 기밀 유지를 위해서 폭발시켜야 해.
That's a prototype. We have to destroy that to keep secrets.
인증 코드를 입력해 주세요.
Please enter authentication code.
인증 코드 코쿠류 알파.
Authentication code: Kokuryu Alpha.
그만둬!
Stop that!
방해하지 마.
Don't stop me.
메타비도 같이 있잖아!
Metabee's there, too!
멋대로 뛰어들었잖아? 나하고는 상관 없어. 폭발에 휘말리고 싶지 않으면 손을 놓으라고 명령하는 건 어때?
He dived to it on his own, and I have nothing to do with that.
If you want to keep him out of explosion, why not command him to let go of it?
뭐라고!? 네 메다로트를 자폭시키고도 아무 생각 안 드냐!?
What!? Don't you feel anything by making your Medarot explode!?
뭐가 그렇게 마음에 안 들어?
Why do you care?
넌 정말-
You really are-
자폭은 못 시킬 테다!
You shall not command self destruction!
자폭 시퀀스 입력이 중단되었습니다. 보안 프로그램을 기동합니다.
Self destruction sequence input has been interrupted. Activating security program.
안 됐네. 이걸로 100분 후에 플라이팔콘은 자폭할 거야.
Too bad. Flyfalcon will destruct itself after 100 minutes.
메타비! 메타비!
Metabee! Metabee!
자폭이라고!?
Self destruct!?
어서 걔한테서 멀어져!
Hurry up and get off that thing!
네가 말하는 것처럼 간단히 내릴 수 있으면 좋았겠다!
I'd really be glad if I could do that so easily!
게다가 얘 어디서 폭발할지도 모르잖아?
Moreover, you don't know where it'll explode!
어떻게든 얠 바닥에 떨어뜨려야 해.
We have to get this onto the ground.
무리하지는 마. 꼭 구해줄 테니까 버티고 있어!
Don't overdo it. I'll save you - just keep it on!
알았다니까!
I know, I know!
메타비! 야!
Metabee! Hey!
젠장, 전파가 안 닿는 곳까지 가 버렸어!
Damn! They went too far to communicate!
참 안됐구나.
Well, too bad for you.
뭐라고!?
What did you say!?
잇키 군.
Ikki.
이 VTOL 제게 빌려 주시죠.
Let me use this VTOL.
음?
Huh?
메타비를 구하러 갈 겁니다.
We're going to rescue Metabee.
그 장난감 말입니까?
You mean, that toy?
그래요. 당신들이 보면 그냥 장난감일지 모르겠지만, 우리에게는 소중한 친구예요!
Yes. You people might think them as toys, but they're friends to us!
애초에 당신이 이걸 조종할 수 있습니까?
First of all, can you even pilot this?
물론이죠. 제트기든 잠수함이든 이 제가 조종할 수 없는 탈것은 없어요.
Of course. Let it be a jet or a submarine - there's nothing I can pilot.
잇키 군, 유즈루 군, 타!
Ikki, Yuzuru, get on!
VTOL 가져갔네.
They took our VTOL.
죄송합니다, 도련님.
I apologize, young master.
뭐, 됐어. 어차피 시간 낭비야.
Well, that's all right. They're wasting their time anyway.
젠장!
Damn!
위험하잖아!
That's dangerous!
찾았다!
I found them!
메타비! 들려?
Metabee! Can you hear me?
잇키냐!
Ikki!?
메타비! 어떻게든 지상으로 못 내려오겠어?
Metabee! Can you make it to the ground anyhow?
나도 아까부터 그럴 생각뿐이야! 얘, 말하는 걸 절대 안 듣잖아! 이게!
I am trying to do that, but this is one stubborn guy! Damn you!
저거다!
That's it!
아침은 싫어하지만 어느 날 돌연
Mornings are not my favorite, but someday on a sudden
자명종 울리기 전에 일어났어
I woke up before my alarm clock rings
내 가슴이 메어지게 괴로워
My wringing heart is so troubled
슬픈 만큼 당신은 연상의 사람
As much as I'm sad, you are older than me
쭉 보고 있어도 닿지 않아
Gazing at you isn't getting me through
키하고 하트
Height and heart
빛나는 미소는
Is the shining smile
우러러 볼 뿐만인 태양?
nothing more than a sun that I admire?
Don't mind 신경쓰지 마
Don't mind, don't make it let you down
My girl 쏘아올리기 전에
To my girl, before you make a dash,
Fight mind 무기력함에 져 버린다면
have a fighting mindset! If you lose to timorousness,
사랑은 잡을 수 없어
you cannot catch the love
차회예고
Preview for Next Episode
최근 잇키의 시험 성적은 최악으로, 아버지께 로보틀 금지를 선언당한다.
Ikki's test scores are all-time low. Ikki's father has declared a ban on Robattle s.
메타비와의 로보틀 콤비 부활을 위해 어떻게든 좋은 점수를 따려고 하는 잇키.
To revive the Robattle pair with Metabee, Ikki's doing anything to get good test scores.
기상천외한 컨닝 작전을 전개한다.
An extraordinary cheating plan begins.
그러나 모모카와가 이끄는 가이로트 군단이 공격을 시작한다.
But Momokawa's Gairot Corps start to attack.
과연 잇키의 컨닝은 성공하는가?
Will Ikki succeed in his cheating?
메다로트 혼의 다음 이야기! 컨닝 대작전
Next time on Medarot Damashii! Cheating Superplan
타올라라, 뜨거운 혼이여!
Let the hot spirit burn up!